Charles Li

Toronto, ON ° M5A 0M8 41CharlesLi@gmail.com ° 647-907-6252

Web Developer Profile

I'm a web developer dedicated to building user-friendly, accessible, and responsive websites and applications. As a former elementary teacher with 10 years of experience, I'm adept at working in a collaborative environment with strong skills in communication, time management, problem-solving, and conflict resolution.

I love reading fantasy novels (finished the Wheel of Time series), discovering new ramen shops while I'm traveling

Selected Skills

HTML5 | CSS | SCSS | JavaScript | JQuery | React | RESTful APIs | Firebase | Responsive Design | Web Accessibility | Github | Paired Programming | Scope Management | Time-management | Communication | Collaboration | Problem Solving | Adaptability

Education

2022	Juno College - Web Development bootcamp
2012 - 2013	Ontario Institute for Studies in Education, University of Toronto • Toronto, ON Bachelor of Education , Primary/Junior
2005 – 2008	University of Toronto • Toronto, ON Honors Bachelors of Science in Psychology, History, and Music

Projects

Creative PSD conversion | JS | HTML | SCSS

An accessible website that is responsive across many screen sizes. Has a working hamburger menu and carousel.

Untitled Project | JS | HTML | SCSS | React | Firebase

An accessible website that is responsive across many screen sizes. Has a working hamburger menu and carousel.

Professional Experience

2019 - 2022 **Homeroom Teacher**, grades 3-4-5

Jean Lumb Public School, Toronto District School Board

• Created safe and inclusive classroom space for over 150 students with lessons designed around student equity and inclusivity

- Collaborated with administration in annual development of staffing model, we placed over 25 educators in their roles
- Transitioned 6 teachers to online teaching through sharing of digital tools, lesson plans, and tech support
- Participated in timetable committee where we created the work schedule for over 50 educators
- Mentored new teachers at the school through co-planning sessions and co-teaching opportunities
- Participated in school improvement committees such as Social/Health and Safety/Tech/Staffing

2014 - 2019 Homeroom, French, and Phys Ed. Teacher, grades 4-8

Toronto District School Board

- Organized and ran events such as Blue Jays school day, French culture night, and concerts for over 500 students and their families
- Coached teams/ran clubs such as the girls/boys basketball teams, chess team, soccer team, Dungeons and Dragons club, homework club, and guitar club
- Piloted first inclusive model at school where we transitioned 8 special education students back into homeroom for language and math
- Taught and designed media literacy lessons to 12 deaf and hard of hearing students, grades 4-7